ever wonder what gives AI its superpowers
想知道是什么赋予了人工智能超能力吗？
but have you ever wondered what
但你有没有想过
is really under the hood
真的在引擎盖下
what makes it so fast  so smart
是什么让它这么快这么聪明
the answer is not the brain of your computer
答案不是你电脑的大脑
it is the soul
它是灵魂
think of the CPU like a master chef
将CPU视为大厨
it is a specialist preparing one
这是一个专家准备一个
complex dish with incredible skill
具有令人难以置信的技巧的复杂菜肴
the GPU is an army of cooks
GPU是一支厨师大军
each one does a simple task
每个人都做一个简单的任务
but they all do it at the exact same time
但他们都同时做
one is a specialist for complex tasks
一个是复杂任务的专家
the other is a master of parallelism  and in AI
另一个是并行和人工智能大师
parallelism is everything
并行就是一切
AI training is not one complex problem
人工智能训练不是一个复杂的问题
it is millions of tiny
它是数百万个微小的
repetitive calculations done over and over again
一遍又一遍地重复计算
and it turns out
结果证明
most AI workloads are not one complex meal
大多数AI工作负载不是一顿复杂的饭
they are thousands of simple ones
它们是成千上万个简单的
the secret ingredient for AI
人工智能的秘密成分
especially deep learning
尤其是深度学习
is a type of math called matrix multiplication
是一种叫做矩阵乘法的数学
a CPU tackles this one calculation at a time
CPU一次处理一个计算
it is precise
很精确
but painfully slow for the sheer volume AI demands
但对于AI的巨大需求来说，速度非常缓慢
a GPU however was built for this
然而，为此构建了一个GPU
its thousands of cores can handle thousands of
它的数千个核心可以处理数千个
these calculations at the exact same time
这些计算同时进行
more cores mean more calculations per second
更多的核心意味着每秒更多的计算
so what does this look like in the real world
那么这在现实世界中是什么样子的呢？
when an AI model analyzes images
当人工智能模型分析图像时
a GPU allows it to scan thousands of pictures at once
GPU允许它一次扫描数千张图片
the core of modern AI is an operation
现代人工智能的核心是操作
called matrix multiplication
称为矩阵乘法
it then predicts the next token across
然后它预测下一个标记
millions of possibilities in parallel
数以百万计的可能性并行
generating human like text in seconds
在几秒钟内生成类似人类的文本
in an autonomous vehicle
在自动驾驶汽车中
the GPU is the brain
GPU就是大脑
it simultaneously processes data from cameras
它同时处理来自摄像头的数据
lidar and radar
激光雷达和雷达
achieving quadrillions of floating
实现万亿浮动
point operations per second
每秒点数
let us go deeper
让我们深入
inside a modern AI focus GPU
在现代AI焦点GPU中
it is not just about raw core count
这不仅仅是原始核心数量
companies like Nvidia have built
像英伟达这样的公司已经建立了
specialized hardware called tensor cores
称为张量核心的专用硬件
they are designed to accelerate the
它们旨在加速
matrix math that AI relies on
AI依赖的矩阵数学
this combined with ultra fast high bandwidth memory
这与超快速高带宽内存相结合
creates the perfect storm for AI workloads
为AI工作负载创造完美风暴
but hardware is useless without software
但是没有软件硬件是没用的
platforms like Nvidia's CUDA
像英伟达的CUDA这样的平台
and AMD's Rocm are the key
AMD的Rocm是关键
frameworks like Tensorflow and
Tensorflow和
Pytorch are built on top of this
Pytorch建立在这个之上
they make it accessible to millions of AI researchers
他们让数百万人工智能研究人员可以使用它
now  this power is not free
现在这种力量不是免费的
GPUs are notoriously power hungry
GPU是出了名的耗电
and their price tags can be astronomical
他们的价格标签可能是天文数字
and the race is far from over
比赛远未结束
companies are pushing the boundaries
公司正在突破界限
with every new generation of hardware
随着每一代新一代硬件
we are even seeing the rise of
我们甚至看到了
custom built AI accelerators
定制的AI加速器
they are designed solely for these massive tasks
它们专为这些庞大的任务而设计
GPU's evolved from drawing pixels on your
GPU是从在您的
screen to becoming the engine of the 21st
屏幕成为21世纪的引擎
century's biggest technological revolution
本世纪最大的技术革命
they are not just graphics cards anymore
它们不再只是显卡了
they are the hardware that is building the future
它们是构建未来的硬件